<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Grow South City</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://growsouthcity.com/</id><updated>2018-06-01T21:44:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>May 2018 Garden Review</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/may-2018-garden.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-01T21:44:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T21:44:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Roderick</name></author><id>tag:growsouthcity.com,2018-06-01:/may-2018-garden.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Spring is nearing its end in the garden as May closes out. The Farewell-to-Spring (&lt;em&gt;Clarkia rubicunda&lt;/em&gt;) is budding and the foggy days of summer will be here soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spring is nearing its end in the garden as May closes out. The Farewell-to-Spring (&lt;em&gt;Clarkia rubicunda&lt;/em&gt;) is budding and the foggy days of summer will be here soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of the native plants bloomed this month. There were small blossoms on the yerba buena (&lt;em&gt;Clinopodium douglasii&lt;/em&gt;) and alum root (&lt;em&gt;Heuchera micrantha&lt;/em&gt;) and much larger blossoms on the Coast Buckwheat (&lt;em&gt;Eriogonum latifolum&lt;/em&gt;; left in image below) and Hummingbird Sage (&lt;em&gt;Salvia spatheca&lt;/em&gt;; right in image below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Sage and buckwheat flowering" src="http://growsouthcity.com/images/20180601-salvia-eriogonum.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly I finally gave up on the avocado tree I planted this last winter; the site I'd chosen was too windy and not well-enough irrigated. I got another and put in in a pot on our new drip irrigation in a more sheltered location; here's hoping it does better! Another new tree is the small oak (&lt;em&gt;Quercus agrifola&lt;/em&gt;?) seedling I found growing as a volunteer (some scrub jay or squirrel evidenly forgot about their dinner!) and transplanted into a small pot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Oak seedling growing" src="http://growsouthcity.com/images/20180601-oak.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I'm looking forward to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mountainwatch.org/plantsale/"&gt;June 2nd Plant Sale&lt;/a&gt; at the Mission Blue nursery. I'd like to grab a Wood Rose (&lt;em&gt;Rosa Gymnocarpa&lt;/em&gt;), a Sticky Monkey-Flower (&lt;em&gt;Mimulus auranticus&lt;/em&gt;), and maybe a fern amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="monthly-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Districting South City</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/districting-south-city.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-05T07:56:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-05T07:56:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Roderick</name></author><id>tag:growsouthcity.com,2018-05-05:/districting-south-city.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;South San Francisco is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/government/district-elections"&gt;switching to district elections&lt;/a&gt; over the next few years (to avoid a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-palmdale-elections-lawsuit-20150506-story.html"&gt;costly legal bill&lt;/a&gt;) and the city's asking for citizen input on how to assign the districts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;South San Francisco is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/government/district-elections"&gt;switching to district elections&lt;/a&gt; over the next few years (to avoid a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-palmdale-elections-lawsuit-20150506-story.html"&gt;costly legal bill&lt;/a&gt;) and the city's asking for citizen input on how to assign the districts. I fun creating and submitting a couple of my own district maps and I thought I'd explain how and where to do your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/government/city-council/district-elections/map-the-districts"&gt;Excel and paper copies of the redistricting maps&lt;/a&gt; available, but I found the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lexington.caliper.com/southsanfrancisco/"&gt;web-based mapping tool&lt;/a&gt; much faster (once I was over the learning curve) because I was able to very quickly see how many people I put in each district and what parcels I could move back and forth between the districts. For the web mapping tool, there's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lexington.caliper.com/southsanfrancisco/help/quickstart/QuickStartGuide.htm"&gt;&amp;quot;quick start&amp;quot; guide available&lt;/a&gt; and you can get to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lexington.caliper.com/southsanfrancisco/"&gt;tool itself here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a throwaway password for the tool, because the website login isn't secure and it's possible a hacker could get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are options for four or five districts that preset the desired number of residents for each district. I chose the five district one; it has the advantage of each council member having few constituents and hopefully therefore being more responsive to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Screenshot of the redistricting web tool" src="http://growsouthcity.com/images/20180505-zoning-map.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're logged in, it looks like the picture above. Besides the zoom and pan tools on the map itself, the main thing you'll be doing is clicking each parcel with the little &amp;quot;cursor with a star&amp;quot; tool or a group of parcels with the &amp;quot;dashed outline&amp;quot; tool and clicking the &amp;quot;green check mark&amp;quot; to add them to the current district (either &amp;quot;New District&amp;quot; or an existing district from the drop down menu). All these tools are in the &amp;quot;Redistricting Toolbox&amp;quot; in the upper left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Some things I learned:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep an eye on the window below the map (&amp;quot;Districts in Plan&amp;quot;) that shows the population deviation from the allowed. Your largest and smallest districts have to be within 1,273 people of each other for the five-district map or the city won't accept it (subtract your lowest negative number from your highest positive number).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Westborough is just slightly too big to make all of the districts evenly balanced; either you need to split it in two or just accept that one of your districts is going to have several hundred extra people. Splitting it is bad for the Voting Rights Act as it's a majority Asian district and you're not supposed to gerrymander minority neighborhoods although I'm not sure how rigorous this is weighed against keeping the neighborhoods the same size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downtown is a little tricky too because it's a majority Latin district (so once again it's difficult to split through), but it's relatively easier to keep a neighborhood here than in Westborough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a bunch of tiny industrial or highway areas you might miss. Click the Plan Integrity menu and then &amp;quot;Find Unassigned Areas&amp;quot; to go through these and add them to your districts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, our current city government is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Council%E2%80%93manager_government"&gt;council-manager system&lt;/a&gt; where the mayor is basically a ceremonial position and the city manager does all the day-to-day management with supervision by the council. I'm not sure how directly-electing a mayor would change the position (versus having the mayor be rotated among council members as it currently is), but I'm curious to hear more about that proposal especially as it seems like a more significant change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you find this useful and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="districting"></category></entry><entry><title>Proposals for the SFPUC Site</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/sfpuc-proposals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-01T17:17:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T17:17:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Roderick</name></author><id>tag:growsouthcity.com,2018-05-01:/sfpuc-proposals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;There are current four proposals for the PUC site; I'm going to walk through the top three here and examine their pluses and minuses. If you'd like to examine them for yourself, they're &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/departments/economic-community-development/puc"&gt;all available from the City's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are current four proposals for the PUC site; I'm going to walk through the top three here and examine their pluses and minuses. If you'd like to examine them for yourself, they're &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/departments/economic-community-development/puc"&gt;all available from the City's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a proposal from Republic Metropolitan that I'm very underwhelmed by. It has 266 pages of filler and is missing the attachment with all the fee schedules. It also scored bottom in the initial competition, but if you'd like to see it for yourself it's at the link above (skip the first 266 pages though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start with, I made a quick score card of the proposals and scored each proposal from 1 to 3 (with 3 being the best). Since these aren't the final proposals and most of the specifics are up to change (e.g. total number of units, height, parking spaces), I tried to pick more qualitative metrics to judge upon to get a idea of the overall thoughtfulness of each proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="41%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="18%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="21%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="20%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;AGI/KASA&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Blake Griggs&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;SummerHill&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Integrated BMR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fee amounts in Proposal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bike friendliness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Open Space&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 (53%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 (59%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (41%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth noting that AGI/KASA and Blake Griggs were the original two &amp;quot;best&amp;quot; proposals until the city council re-expanded the field (for poorly described reasons), but I found things to like in the SummerHill proposal too; specifically how the below-market-rate units were integrated throughout the proposal rather than being put into their own building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we have to pick a winner then between AGI/KASA and Blake Griggs I would probably choose AGI/KASA; besides the items in the table, their proposal included &amp;quot;maker&amp;quot; or PDR space (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sfhac.org/filling-ground-floors-san-francisco-makers/"&gt;see a fuller description by one of their co-developers, SFMade&lt;/a&gt;) which I think is a novel idea that harkens back to our heritage as an industrial city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, all three are good proposals though and if we don't select AGI/KASA, I would be happy with the other two developers. Whatever happens, we must select a developer though; if no developer is chosen, the PUC property goes to auction and the city loses much of its ability to influence the resulting construction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="sfpuc"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/intro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-17T21:46:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T21:46:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Roderick</name></author><id>tag:growsouthcity.com,2018-04-17:/intro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Welcome! Recently some of our more conservative neighbors have become upset over plans to build housing in South San Francisco. Our goal with this site will hopefully provide some much-needed perspective on how we can grow South San Francisco and improve our city socially, environmentally, and horticulturally.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome! Recently some of our more conservative neighbors have become upset over plans to build housing in South San Francisco. Our goal with this site will hopefully provide some much-needed perspective on how we can grow South San Francisco and improve our city socially, environmentally, and horticulturally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't yet, please &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.change.org/p/karyl-matsumoto-help-us-build-homes-in-south-san-francisco"&gt;sign our petition&lt;/a&gt; to support more housing in South City or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.smdailyjournal.com/opinion/guest_perspectives/in-defense-of-high-density-housing-near-south-city-bart/article_920a9eac-475a-11e8-bc6c-b33c11c3201f.html"&gt;read this opinion piece&lt;/a&gt; on why we need to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="View over South San Francisco from San Bruno Mountain" src="http://growsouthcity.com/images/20180417-ssf-view.jpg" /&gt;
</content><category term="intro"></category></entry></feed>