<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Grow South City - housing</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/feeds/housing.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://growsouthcity.com/</id><updated>2018-05-01T17:17:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Proposals for the SFPUC Site</title><link href="http://growsouthcity.com/sfpuc-proposals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-01T17:17:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T17:17:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Roderick</name></author><id>tag:growsouthcity.com,2018-05-01:/sfpuc-proposals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;There are current four proposals for the PUC site; I'm going to walk through the top three here and examine their pluses and minuses. If you'd like to examine them for yourself, they're &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/departments/economic-community-development/puc"&gt;all available from the City's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are current four proposals for the PUC site; I'm going to walk through the top three here and examine their pluses and minuses. If you'd like to examine them for yourself, they're &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssf.net/departments/economic-community-development/puc"&gt;all available from the City's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a proposal from Republic Metropolitan that I'm very underwhelmed by. It has 266 pages of filler and is missing the attachment with all the fee schedules. It also scored bottom in the initial competition, but if you'd like to see it for yourself it's at the link above (skip the first 266 pages though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start with, I made a quick score card of the proposals and scored each proposal from 1 to 3 (with 3 being the best). Since these aren't the final proposals and most of the specifics are up to change (e.g. total number of units, height, parking spaces), I tried to pick more qualitative metrics to judge upon to get a idea of the overall thoughtfulness of each proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="41%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="18%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="21%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="20%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;AGI/KASA&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Blake Griggs&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;SummerHill&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Integrated BMR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fee amounts in Proposal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bike friendliness&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Open Space&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 (53%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 (59%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (41%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth noting that AGI/KASA and Blake Griggs were the original two &amp;quot;best&amp;quot; proposals until the city council re-expanded the field (for poorly described reasons), but I found things to like in the SummerHill proposal too; specifically how the below-market-rate units were integrated throughout the proposal rather than being put into their own building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we have to pick a winner then between AGI/KASA and Blake Griggs I would probably choose AGI/KASA; besides the items in the table, their proposal included &amp;quot;maker&amp;quot; or PDR space (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.sfhac.org/filling-ground-floors-san-francisco-makers/"&gt;see a fuller description by one of their co-developers, SFMade&lt;/a&gt;) which I think is a novel idea that harkens back to our heritage as an industrial city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, all three are good proposals though and if we don't select AGI/KASA, I would be happy with the other two developers. Whatever happens, we must select a developer though; if no developer is chosen, the PUC property goes to auction and the city loses much of its ability to influence the resulting construction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="sfpuc"></category></entry></feed>